<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-23T22:23:17-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Kelsey Humphries Portfolio</title><subtitle>design, research, strategy</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Branding Brand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/brandingbrand/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Branding Brand" /><published>2013-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/brandingbrand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/brandingbrand/">&lt;p&gt;In the fall of 2013, I joined the UX team at Branding Brand. I’ve had many different responsibilities during my two years at the company, and I currently am working on designing new products for the company.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/brandingbrand/wireframe.png&quot; alt=&quot;bb-wireframe&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;wireframes&quot;&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I contributed wireframes for many different client projects. These ranged from mobile commerce sites to apps to responsive sites. Most recently, I’ve been focused on responsive designs for enterprise products.
I’m a big believer in using the right tool for the job, and during my time at Branding Brand I’ve created wireframes in Balsamiq, Axure, and Sketch, with varying levels of fidelity and interactivity.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/brandingbrand/prototype.png&quot; alt=&quot;bb-prototype&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototyping&quot;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my biggest areas of growth at Branding Brand has been my technical skills. Although I knew basic HTML/CSS/Javascript before joining the company, I’ve had the chance to really grow in my understanding of how the web works. I’ve made several interactive prototypes that were shared widely in the company to demonstrate new interactions, and eventually incorporated into many of Branding Brand’s client sites. I’m always trying to push myself out of my comfort zone, and recently completed a prototype using Ember, Ember-Data and node.js.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/brandingbrand/animation.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bb-animate&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;
Animations and transitions can be so important when communicating an interaction. In order to convey animation ideas to clients, I created several videos and prototypes, using After Effects and Framer.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/brandingbrand/abtest.png&quot; alt=&quot;bb-abtest&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ab-testing&quot;&gt;A/B Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was responsible for regularly testing patterns and interactions to help develop a library of best practices for mobile commerce. I would design the tests and interpret the results. Often, I would also implement simple tests myself. This was a great introduction to data-driven decision-making and experimental test design.
I also regularly evaluated client sites and documented recommendations for future A/B tests. This was mostly based on heuristic evaluation and the results of past tests.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/brandingbrand/research.png&quot; alt=&quot;bb-research&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-testing&quot;&gt;User Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I helped to introduce user testing practices at Branding Brand and conducted over 15 usability studies. I tested client sites with basic commerce tasks, such as finding a product, adding to cart, and completing checkout. The findings from these tests revealed issues and bugs that we would not have been able to catch otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-design&quot;&gt;Product Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2015, I joined the product team at Branding Brand as the only designer. I have been responsible for user research, wireframes, visual design, and usability testing of multiple products. I’ve worked closely with the product manager to help define product requirements and user stories. We’ve been fortunate to have a dedicated prototyper on the team, and I’ve been responsible for helping to rapidly iterate on our prototype concepts.
I’ve also worked on developing design principles to help create a framework for making consistent and informed design decisions.
Although I unfortunately can’t disclose the final results for many of these due to confidential information, &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kelsey.humphries@gmail.com&quot;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to chat more!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In the fall of 2013, I joined the UX team at Branding Brand. I’ve had many different responsibilities during my two years at the company, and I currently am working on designing new products for the company. Wireframes I contributed wireframes for many different client projects. These ranged from mobile commerce sites to apps to responsive sites. Most recently, I’ve been focused on responsive designs for enterprise products. I’m a big believer in using the right tool for the job, and during my time at Branding Brand I’ve created wireframes in Balsamiq, Axure, and Sketch, with varying levels of fidelity and interactivity. Prototyping One of my biggest areas of growth at Branding Brand has been my technical skills. Although I knew basic HTML/CSS/Javascript before joining the company, I’ve had the chance to really grow in my understanding of how the web works. I’ve made several interactive prototypes that were shared widely in the company to demonstrate new interactions, and eventually incorporated into many of Branding Brand’s client sites. I’m always trying to push myself out of my comfort zone, and recently completed a prototype using Ember, Ember-Data and node.js. Animations and transitions can be so important when communicating an interaction. In order to convey animation ideas to clients, I created several videos and prototypes, using After Effects and Framer. A/B Testing I was responsible for regularly testing patterns and interactions to help develop a library of best practices for mobile commerce. I would design the tests and interpret the results. Often, I would also implement simple tests myself. This was a great introduction to data-driven decision-making and experimental test design. I also regularly evaluated client sites and documented recommendations for future A/B tests. This was mostly based on heuristic evaluation and the results of past tests. User Testing I helped to introduce user testing practices at Branding Brand and conducted over 15 usability studies. I tested client sites with basic commerce tasks, such as finding a product, adding to cart, and completing checkout. The findings from these tests revealed issues and bugs that we would not have been able to catch otherwise. Product Design In February 2015, I joined the product team at Branding Brand as the only designer. I have been responsible for user research, wireframes, visual design, and usability testing of multiple products. I’ve worked closely with the product manager to help define product requirements and user stories. We’ve been fortunate to have a dedicated prototyper on the team, and I’ve been responsible for helping to rapidly iterate on our prototype concepts. I’ve also worked on developing design principles to help create a framework for making consistent and informed design decisions. Although I unfortunately can’t disclose the final results for many of these due to confidential information, reach out if you’d like to chat more!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oliver</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oliver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oliver" /><published>2013-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oliver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oliver/">&lt;p&gt;For many people, travel is addicting. But when it comes down to actually planning a trip? Totally different story.
Expedia has been the world’s largest online travel booking site for over 15 years, so they are very familiar with the pain points in the travel planning process. They enlisted our five person team (via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hcii.cmu.edu/academics/mhci/capstone-project&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MHCI&lt;/a&gt;) to investigate characteristics that make experiences like Pinterest, Pandora, and Groupon so addicting. Is there a way to apply those principles of habitual discovery to how people think about travel in their everyday lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-definition&quot;&gt;Project Definition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began with a kick-off meeting to define the initial scope of the project and create a hunt statement that would shape our research and synthesis process for the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt;Our goal: “to engage travelers through habitual discovery, delightful planning, and confident decision making“.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-width&quot; src=&quot;/img/oliver/1-kickoff.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research&quot;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began our research process with a literature review and competitive analysis of both discovery and travel services. This helped us to understand the relationships between existing sites and identify leaders in different areas.
We then began our field research, which consisted of talking to over 102 participants across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/2-research.png&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/2-research.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-research&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contextual interviews&lt;/strong&gt; consisted of visiting a participant’s home and observing how they naturally used discovery and travel websites. These interviews revealed how people typically interact with these services and what keeps them coming back on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guerrilla interviews&lt;/strong&gt; were conducted by traveling to a popular travel destination and asking people about their travel planning process. These retrospective interviews gave insight into how people plan travel and whether their plans change once traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joy visits&lt;/strong&gt; centered around talking to people who had activities they were passionate about, such as dancing, art, theatre, games, or biking. The goal here was to learn more about delight and flow outside of the digital space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal studies&lt;/strong&gt; consisted of asking participants to fill out a journal page each day detailing their thoughts and feelings about travel, as well as any travel planning activities. This helped uncover how travel fits into people’s everyday lives. We conducted both two-week and two-month studies, in order to see the travel planning process over longer stretches of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;synthesis&quot;&gt;Synthesis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the field research yielded a lot of data to sift through. The main method we used to synthesize the data was affinity diagramming, in which each data point becomes a short note on a piece of paper. Notes are then grouped based on similarities, revealing the overarching themes and trends in the data. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/3-affinity.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-affinity&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/timeline.pdf&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/4-timeline.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-timeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also created a new synthesis method to help us deal with unpacking the data from the long-term journal studies. Each participant’s journal responses about travel planning were mapped onto a &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/timeline.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;timeline&lt;/a&gt;.
Based on trends in the data, we identified five key stages of travel planning. We highlighted each data point based on which of the stages it corresponded to. This allowed us to see similarities across participants and identify several different travel planning personas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;insights&quot;&gt;Insights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the data, we identified three key insights that would help inform our design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confident researching and organizing make travel planning more delightful and less stressful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exploration is more enjoyable when the content is relevant, but there is still a desire for something novel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiences are better when they are shared with others, but coordination between people can be difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also found five stages of travel planning from our journal studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/5-stages.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-stages&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we found that people did not always move linearly through these stages, and different people often had different methods of planning travel. We identified nine main travel planning profiles and grouped each of our 36 journal participants into one of these profiles.
For example, people who fell into the Price Checkers profile tended to spend a disproportionate amount of time in the investigating stage, and often completed it in parallel with the refining stage.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/6-pricecheckers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-pricecheckers&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visioning&quot;&gt;Visioning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on our findings from the research stage, we moved into visioning. The goal throughout visioning was to generate design ideas from our insights and to narrow them down to find one that would be best suited for our hunt statement and project scope.
We began with ideation based on our affinity diagram and travel profiles, during which we “walked the wall” (actually several walls) of data and wrote down any design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-width&quot; src=&quot;/img/oliver/7-visioning.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We narrowed these ideas down to our top ten most intriguing ones and created &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/storyboards.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;storyboards&lt;/a&gt; for each of them. We then showed these storyboards in a speed dating format to our journal participants in order to elicit feedback and narrow down the ideas even further.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/8-storyboards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-storyboards&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/9-clientvisioning-alt.JPG&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/9-clientvisioning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-visioning&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also conducted a visioning workshop with our clients, after presenting our research and insights to them. We did several group design activities together, such as brainstorming where a hypothetical new service might fit into the existing landscape of products.&lt;br /&gt;
To help pull together all of these different methods and ideas, we created a user journey diagram that outlined how a user might move through the travel planning process. We also created an &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/journeytable.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;accompanying chart&lt;/a&gt; that outlined user needs, thoughts, feelings, barriers, touchpoints, and service content for each stage in the user journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/10-userjourney.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-userjourney&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help us narrow down our feature set, we also created an &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/achievability.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;achievability matrix&lt;/a&gt;, where we mapped features based on how impactful and feasible they were. We primarily chose features from the upper right quadrant of the matrix.
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/achievability.pdf&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/11-achievability.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-achievability&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we created three design principles to help guide our future design decisions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel planning should be quick and effortless.&lt;/strong&gt; We found that many people dreaded travel planning because of how time consuming it tended to be. We wanted to make sure our solution helped to alleviate this problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People should be able to choose how they plan travel.&lt;/strong&gt; Based on our travel profiles from our research findings, we knew that different people tended to plan travel in different ways. We wanted to make sure to support people’s natural way of travel planning, rather than try to force them into a planning profile that didn’t make sense to them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confident decision-making requires relevant information.&lt;/strong&gt; We found that people often struggled to make a definite commitment to their travel plans, and this often stemmed from feeling like they were missing key information. We wanted to make sure to include the information needed for people to feel secure in their decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rapid-iteration&quot;&gt;Rapid Iteration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wrapping up our research and visioning, we moved on to design. We created a weekly iteration cycle where we would design and build the next iteration in the early part of the week, receive feedback from our faculty advisors and clients, and then take it to test with users every Friday.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/12-cycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-cycle&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/13-paper-full.jpg&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/13-paper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-paper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/14-pop-full.png&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/14-pop.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-pop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this iteration cycle, we created 8 different prototypes. Throughout the design-build-test cycle, our underlying concept changed twice, with smaller iterations within each concept.
We initially created paper prototypes to test early ideas.
These paper prototypes became clickable prototypes using POP and then we moved to Flinto for more robust interactions.
Our final concept was prototyped as an actual iOS application, and we shared it for testing using TestFlight.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concept-video&quot;&gt;Concept Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our biggest challenge was narrowing down the scope of our project. We had unearthed so many problems with the travel planning process that it was hard to cut down the feature list. Our initial prototype attempted to solve too many problems at once, which of course resulted in it not doing a good job of addressing any of them. Throughout the iteration cycle, we continued to fine-tune our scope until we were focusing solely on activities to do while traveling and the act of discovering new things to do. Here is a concept video for Oliver, our final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-embed&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/72852013?color=ffffff&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;title=0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-designs&quot;&gt;Final Designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application centers around the discovery screen, where Oliver, an intelligent octopus facilitator, suggests new activities. The user then has the choice to hide, favorite, or skip each suggestion, and Oliver is able to learn from this input in order to better tailor his suggestions.
Based on our insights from our research, we knew that limiting the information presented was important to users. We included a few simple filters to help limit the scope of discovery, while still allowing for novel suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;break-out&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/15-discovery-full.png&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/15-discovery.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-discovery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/16-filters-full.png&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/16-filters.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-filters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users save activities they are interested in to their Favorites list, and keep these activities in mind for the next time they are visiting a city.
When actually planning a trip, they create an itinerary and add items from their Favorites, or they can just ask Oliver to suggest an activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;break-out&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/17-favorites-full.png&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/17-favorites.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-favorites&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/18-itinerary-full.png&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/oliver/18-itinerary.png&quot; alt=&quot;oliver-itinerary&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about our process, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;http://hciresearch4.hcii.cs.cmu.edu/M-HCI/2013/Wanderlust/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;project website&lt;/a&gt;.
We also created two books detailing our &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/WanderlustResearchReport.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;spring research process&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href=&quot;/img/oliver/WanderlustDesignReport.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;summer design process&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">For many people, travel is addicting. But when it comes down to actually planning a trip? Totally different story. Expedia has been the world’s largest online travel booking site for over 15 years, so they are very familiar with the pain points in the travel planning process. They enlisted our five person team (via MHCI) to investigate characteristics that make experiences like Pinterest, Pandora, and Groupon so addicting. Is there a way to apply those principles of habitual discovery to how people think about travel in their everyday lives? Project Definition We began with a kick-off meeting to define the initial scope of the project and create a hunt statement that would shape our research and synthesis process for the next few months. Our goal: “to engage travelers through habitual discovery, delightful planning, and confident decision making“.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pico</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pico/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pico" /><published>2013-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2013-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pico</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pico/">&lt;p&gt;When families are separated by distance, coordinating communication becomes difficult. Pico is a mobile application that aims to provide a personal way for families to connect using their smartphone cameras.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/connect.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-connect&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;user-research&quot;&gt;User Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted initial interviews with parents and asked about the challenges they faced in connecting with their children. From there, we narrowed our scope to focus on families with children in college and conducted interviews with three sets of parents and children about how they share information and keep in contact. Many families struggled with coordinating their busy schedules and how to determine which information was appropriate to share. We also found that pictures were a powerful communication tool for sharing important family moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;pull-quote&quot;&gt; We identified a need for  a service that gives families a personal, engaging way to connect that is easy enough to fit into their busy lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about our research and concept &lt;a href=&quot;/img/pico/PicoResearch.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;paper-prototyping&quot;&gt;Paper Prototyping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came up with a concept that would allow families to share glimpses of their lives quickly and easily using their smartphone camera. After creating quick paper mockups of the interface, we tested them with potential users to gather feedback about both the concept and the interface. We learned that the idea of sharing photos was intriguing to people, but there would need to be a unique hook to get them to invest time in a new app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full-width&quot; src=&quot;/img/pico/paper2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wireframes&quot;&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting on visual design, we spent some time defining the interactions, particularly around creating a collage and uploading photos.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/chooselayout.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-chooselayout&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/takephoto.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-takephoto&quot; class=&quot;side-by&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-designs&quot;&gt;Final Designs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the entire concept of Pico centers around a lightweight, quick way to share moments with family members or friends, a big challenge was figuring out how to keep the content from becoming overwhelming. We didn’t want one person to be able to overwhelm the feed of photos and dominate the conversation. We also wanted to encourage curation, sharing a glimpse of a moment rather than 100 photos of the same moment. Although we discussed various ways of limiting information, such as a daily limit on how many photos could be added, none of them felt quite right, especially since we hoped to have people returning to the app often. We finally settled on the model of creating group collages centered around a theme or question. Each person in the group would only be able to contribute one photo to each collage, but multiple collages could be in progress at any point in time.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/current_picos.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-current&quot; class=&quot;side-by img-shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/carousel.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-carousel&quot; class=&quot;side-by img-shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-layout&quot; class=&quot;side-by img-shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/theme.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-theme&quot; class=&quot;side-by img-shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can choose from several preset layouts and can either create their own theme, or have one randomly generated for them. They also have the options of seeing the collage’s progress as others add photos, or waiting to be surprised until the collage is complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concept-video&quot;&gt;Concept Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-embed&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/66476201?color=ffffff&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/pico-prototype/index.htm&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/pico/prototype.png&quot; alt=&quot;pico-prototype&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interactive-prototype&quot;&gt;Interactive Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created an interactive prototype, using Fireworks, which can be accessed &lt;a href=&quot;/pico-prototype/index.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For the best experience, visit the link on an iPhone and save the page to your home screen. This will allow the prototype to behave more like an actual application.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When families are separated by distance, coordinating communication becomes difficult. Pico is a mobile application that aims to provide a personal way for families to connect using their smartphone cameras.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Check Me Out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/checkmeout/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Check Me Out" /><published>2012-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/checkmeout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/checkmeout/">&lt;p&gt;The current user experience for grocery shopping is often confusing and frustrating. Our team looked at redesigning that experience to be efficient and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-survey&quot;&gt;Initial Survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began by finding out current frustrations that occur during the grocery shopping experience. From an initial survey, we identified the following needs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I always forget something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t want to spend too much money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can’t find what I’m looking for&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel overwhelmed when choosing between items&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I dislike the store environment and having to spend time there&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t know which store has the best prices/selection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The store does not have what I want&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want an ethically responsible product&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want more information about the food I’m buying&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to buy healthy items without spending too much&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I find it difficult to come up with new recipes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The total price is higher than expected, but I feel bad removing items during checkout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-site-interviews&quot;&gt;On-site Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also visited a grocery store to conduct on-site interviews and asked people to give a quick retrospective account of their grocery shopping experience that day. One employee told us that people ask where items are located every three minutes. We also timed the checkout time of several customers and found on average the process took &lt;em&gt;8 minutes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-tool&quot;&gt;Make Tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/maketool.png&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-maketool&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; /&gt;
Next we used a make tool to validate our findings and find more about the different types of shoppers. We gave participants a map of a grocery store and asked them to sketch out their route through the store while thinking aloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this exercise, we identified two main groups of shoppers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Planners&lt;/strong&gt; tend to have a structured list and go down most aisles. They are efficient and prefer self-checkout.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/planners.png&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-planners&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grabbers&lt;/strong&gt; tend to be more spontaneous and often shop without a list. They stick to the perimeter of the store and generally buy fewer items.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/grabbers.png&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-grabbers&quot; class=&quot;article-width&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concept-maps&quot;&gt;Concept Maps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created concept maps to both visualize the current grocery shopping process and to also understand how the system we were designing could help to alleviate some of the current frustrations. We highlighted the user load to understand how our system would help the user.
The concept map of the current grocery shopping experience placed a heavy load on the user (highlighted in pink).
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/checkmeout/oldconcept-full.gif&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/oldconcept.gif&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-oldconcept&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We focused our solution on reducing the cognitive load for grocery shoppers.
&lt;a href=&quot;/img/checkmeout/newconcept-full.gif&quot; class=&quot;half-width&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/newconcept.gif&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-newconcept&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&quot;video-embed&quot; src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/136459565?color=ffffff&amp;amp;title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;506&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/checkmeout/scanner.png&quot; alt=&quot;cmo-scanner&quot; class=&quot;float-right&quot; style=&quot;width:250px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final solution can be seen in action in the video above. We designed a scanner and smartphone dock to accompany a smartphone app. The app would help shoppers to create and manage lists on their smartphones and the scanner would allow shoppers to ring up items as they go, eliminating the need for checking out. The final solution saves time and money for both consumers and grocery stores and could be implemented with minimal overhaul to current shopping carts and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The current user experience for grocery shopping is often confusing and frustrating. Our team looked at redesigning that experience to be efficient and enjoyable. Initial Survey We began by finding out current frustrations that occur during the grocery shopping experience. From an initial survey, we identified the following needs: I always forget something I don’t want to spend too much money I can’t find what I’m looking for I feel overwhelmed when choosing between items I dislike the store environment and having to spend time there I don’t know which store has the best prices/selection The store does not have what I want I want an ethically responsible product I want more information about the food I’m buying I want to buy healthy items without spending too much I find it difficult to come up with new recipes The total price is higher than expected, but I feel bad removing items during checkout</summary></entry></feed>